Previously on the show. General Balloon was being over-protective of his students.
上集說到，球將軍過分保護學生
He forbade them from playing football.
禁止他們踢足球
But eventually, the students had to play the forbidden football
不料最後卻要用他所禁止的足球
to save Balloon City.
來拯救氣球城
General Balloon learned his lesson about letting the kids explore themselves.
球將軍終於懂得了放手讓學生成長
What will happen next?
那麼接下來又會發生什麼呢？
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: Dreams Come True"
《奇幻天空島之 夢想成真》
A marathon competition?
馬拉松比賽？
Fantastic.
太好了
If I wear my new invention, electric shoes, I'll be able to catch the goats.
穿上我新發明的這雙電鞋 肯定能捉到羊
When I run in them, they'll give off electricity to attack the goats in front.
只要穿著它跑步，鞋子就會自動發電 攻擊前方的羊
Right after knocking the goats out, I'll go over and help.
到時候小羊一暈倒 我就趁機上前幫忙
That way, I can get all the goats under everyone's noses!
這就能神不知鬼不覺地 在大家面前捉羊了
Let's test them out now.
先試驗一下
Why do I get electrocuted every time I stop?
怎麼一停下來就有電啊？
I was the only one who couldn't complete the marathon last time.
上次馬拉松只有我跑不完全程
I will finish it this time!
今年我無論如何也要跑完
Let's start training!
訓練開始
I can't. This is as far as I can go. I can't make it after all.
不行，到極限了，果然還是不行
If I run at this speed, I won't get electrocuted.
這…這個速度電擊終於停了
He's so amazing!
他太厲害了！
Paddi, are you not going to train?
懶羊羊，你真的不練習嗎？
Marathons are so tiring.
馬拉松可累了
I'll just pretend to run on that day.
比賽開始的時候我隨便跑跑
That'll be enough.
意思一下就可以了
Let's start training then.
那我們去練習吧
What a stroke of luck.
真是天助我也啊
Though my electric shoes aren't working well, I've found the goats.
雖然電鞋用不上，但卻發現小羊了
This is my chance.
機會來了
Master!
師父！
Master? You've got the wrong person.
什麼師父？你認錯人了
Come on, little goats.
快來吧，小羊們
Oh, no!
哎呀！
Master, did you come to save me?
師父，你來救我啦？
You're not getting away this time.
你們是逃不掉了
Master!
師父！
What do you want?
你到底要幹麼？
Master, I'm Sixie.
師父，我叫小六
Ever since I've seen you running, I'd hoped to become your student.
自從看見你跑步之後 我就想拜您為師
Please train me for the marathon.
請您訓練我跑馬拉松吧
I don't know how to run for a marathon.
我哪裡會跑馬拉松啊？
I'm not afraid of training. Please train me.
我不怕辛苦的，請您訓練我吧
I'll just say yes and find an excuse to get rid of him.
要不就答應他，再用一些事支開他
I don't want him to cause me any more trouble.
省得他又來搗亂
Master?
師父？
All right. Come to my place tomorrow.
好吧，明天到我家來
Yes, sir!
好！
All right, listen up.
好，話不多說
For the first part of the training, buy me all these things.
訓練第一項，把這些東西都買回來
What are you waiting for? Go!
愣著幹麼？快去！
Yes, sir!
是！
Finally, I'm left in peace to plot my scheme for catching goats.
終於沒有人打擾我設計 最新版的捉羊計劃了
I'm ready to catch those goats during the marathon.
馬拉松當天的捉羊計劃我都準備好了
I'll put invisible walls on the path and lay traps.
在跑道上建隱形牆、佈陷阱
They'll fall into the traps one by one, then I can take them with me.
到時候小羊在跑道中了陷阱 我就可以趁機把他們帶走
Master, I'm back!
師父，我回來了！
That was quick.
怎麼這麼快？
I bought everything online.
現在上網就能買東西了
I need to think of something to get rid of him again.
得想個辦法再支開他才行啊
Go after that car for me. I left something in it.
趕緊去幫我追那輛車 我有東西落在上面了
I don't see a car though.
哪裡有汽車？
Use this to look for it.
用這個看
Let's get to work.
開始工作
I called the driver and got the car back.
我打電話讓汽車回來了
You can't use a mobile phone.
不能使用手機
Now take the trash out to the furthest dumping ground.
現在幫我把垃圾丟到最遠的垃圾場
Yes, sir!
是！
Now I'll have some time to work.
終於有時間工作了
Where's my toolbox?
我的工具箱呢？
Come back! That's not trash!
回來，那不是垃圾
Run inside this circle until I get back.
在我回來之前 你就一直在圈子裡邊原地跑
Don't step out of the circle.
不能走出這個圈
Yes, sir!
是！
I finally got rid of him.
終於擺脫他了
Paddi, let's train. You need to work out to be a man.
懶羊羊，快來練習吧 只有運動才能造就男子漢啊
It's too tiring, and I'm not bothered about being a man.
訓練太累了 我也沒有興趣做什麼男子漢
Wolffy will catch you one day if you go on like this.
你這樣遲早會被灰太狼抓走的
That's it.
沒辦法了
I'm going to force you to train with me today.
今天就算強迫你 也要讓你跟著我特訓
Watch out!
快躲開！
Don't step out of the circle.
不能走出這個圈
That was close. Why didn't you duck?
剛才那麼危險，你幹麼不躲開？
My master told me to train in here. He told me not to step out of the circle.
師父讓我待在圈裡訓練，不准出來
What kind of training is that?
這算哪門子的訓練啊？
That must've been a test Master gave me.
這一定是師父給我的考驗
He wants me to do well in the marathon.
為了要在馬拉松比賽裡跑出好成績
It's enough as long as we take part. Why must we do well in it?
重在參與就行了 為什麼一定要有好成績？
I'm always the only one who doesn't complete the marathon.
每次跑馬拉松比賽 只有我沒有跑完全程
I must work hard this time to prove I can do it!
這次我必須要努力證明自己
I'm sure you'll be able to do it.
你一定能做到的
Let's go back and train.
那我們也回去練習吧
I'm so tired. Can I take a nap first?
我好睏啊，我先睡一覺再練可以嗎？
Come now.
現在就來
I'll get you all tomorrow.
明天就可以抓到你們了
Keep going!
努力！
Keep going! Hang in there...
努力...堅持...努力..
Him again? He's distracting me from setting traps.
又是他？吵著人家佈置陷阱
Keep going!
努力
Congratulations. You've passed the test. You're ready to graduate.
恭喜你成功通過考驗，順利畢業
Really, Master?
師父，真的嗎？
Yes. This is your graduation gift from me.
真的，這雙鞋是我送給你的畢業禮物
Master!
師父！
I wish you all the best tomorrow.
祝你明天可以成功
All right, go get some rest.
好了，快點回去休息吧
I will do my best!
我一定會努力的
Now I'll lay my traps and wait for the marathon to begin tomorrow.
我趕緊去把陷阱佈置好 就等明天開賽了
-Are you ready? -Are you nervous?
-你準備好了嗎？ -好緊張
These shoes are so cool! They glow every time I move.
好酷的跑鞋，只要我動一下 居然就會發光
Believe me, I will do well this time.
小美，相信我 這一次我一定能跑好的
Eat up... Grow fatter.
吃吧…吃肥一點
Get in your positions!
請各位參賽選手各就各位！
Ready... go!
預備，開始！
I've run for an entire minute. Time to take a break.
跑了整整一分鐘了，先休息一下
A break? Let me help you.
要休息嗎？讓我來扶你吧
Sure.
好啊
Wolffy!
灰太狼！
Help...
救命啊…
This contestant is working really hard.
這一屆的選手真的很拼搏
He's crying for help, but he's still running so fast.
喊救命了還在堅持跑
I can't do it anymore.
我快不行了
Run all you want.
你儘管跑吧
Master is running with me! He's here to cheer me on.
沒想到師父也和我一起跑、幫我打氣
Let's go!
衝啊！
Don't push yourself.
別勉強了
Come take a break with me if you can't go on.
跑不動就跟我下去休息吧
What's going on? You?
怎麼回事啊？你...
Master!
師父！
Stop following me!
不要跟著我！
I must catch up with you.
我一定會追上師父的
I knew it. I know Master's training works!
我就知道師父對我的訓練是有用的
An invisible wall? No!
隱形牆？不！
Paddi, you ran even faster than us.
懶羊羊 沒想到你跑得比我們還要快啊
I guess my training worked.
看來我對你的訓練是真有效
Wolffy?
灰太狼？
Yes! I finished the marathon!
太好了！我真的跑完全程了
Sixie! You...
小六你…
Master!
師父！
This is for you.
送給你
Thanks to you, I finished the marathon. Thank you.
多虧了師父我才能夠跑完全程 謝謝你
You did it all by yourself.
這是你自己爭取回來的榮譽
Keep your skill with you.
好好保管它
Master, you're the best!
師父對我最好了！
TO BE CONTINUED 2754 DAYS FROM SETTING SAIL
（未完待續 距離啟航還2754剩天）